<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>City of Belvedere News</title>
    <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news</link>
    <description>Official news and updates from the City of Belvedere, California</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:14:33 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</webMaster>
    <ns0:link href="https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Marin ADU Fair + Open House: Saturday, October 4</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/marin-adu-fair-open-house-saturday-october-4/</link>
      <description>Ready to explore what's possible with an ADU? Join us for Marin County's ADU Fair on Saturday, October 4 from 9-12:15pm. Meet local experts - Planners, Architects, Lenders and Builders- and learn how an ADU can add flexibility, income or housing to your property. Belvedere's own Planning and Building Director Rebecca Markwick will be on...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/marin-adu-fair-open-house-saturday-october-4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Go Bags for Belvedere Residents: Friday, October 10</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/free-go-bags-for-belvedere-residents-friday-october-10/</link>
      <description>The Be Ready Belvedere team wants every resident to have their own Go Bag - in case we’re ever ordered to evacuate our homes during an emergency. To help jump start this effort, they’ll be handing out one free backpack per household, underwritten by the Belvedere Community Foundation, to the first 100 Belvedere residents who...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/free-go-bags-for-belvedere-residents-friday-october-10/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belvedere Home Made Film Festival: Friday, October 10</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belvedere-home-made-film-festival-friday-october-10/</link>
      <description>Join your neighbors in Belvedere Community Park on Friday, October 10 at 6:30pm for the second annual Belvedere Home Made Film Festival - an evening of locally-created short films celebrating community, sponsored in part by the City of Belvedere. Come early to this free, family-friendly event to find a good spot for your blanket or low-back chairs....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belvedere-home-made-film-festival-friday-october-10/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News from the Parks, Open Spaces &amp; Lanes Committee</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news-from-the-parks-open-spaces-lanes-committee/</link>
      <description>The next time you stroll through Community Park or hike up one of our lanes, give a nod of thanks to Belvedere’s Parks, Open Spaces and Lanes Committee (POSLC). This volunteer committee collaborates closely with our Department of Public Works (DPW) to oversee and enhance city-owned property, including 23 lanes, 4 parks, the children’s playground...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news-from-the-parks-open-spaces-lanes-committee/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coastal Cleanup &amp; Treasure Hunt: Saturday, Sept. 20</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/coastal-cleanup-treasure-hunt-saturday-sept-20/</link>
      <description>Join fellow nature lovers and treasure hunters at the San Rafael Avenue seawall near West Shore Road on Saturday, September 20 from 9am to noon for California Coastal Cleanup Day. Wear sturdy shoes and bring work gloves. This year, special “trash” items will be hidden at cleanup sites across the state, making it the world's...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/coastal-cleanup-treasure-hunt-saturday-sept-20/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Department Upgrades to Flock Safety System</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-upgrades-to-flock-safety-system/</link>
      <description>This summer, Belvedere upgraded its automated license plate reader cameras to the Flock Safety System. Flock is widely adopted by Marin County law enforcement agencies and is becoming the industry standard throughout California. This new platform improves accuracy, has greater search capabilities, and integratesdirectly with surrounding agencies. This means our police can receive real-time alerts...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-upgrades-to-flock-safety-system/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-4/</link>
      <description>Police Department Update To address the recent staffing challenge, City Manager Zadnik reported that he is contracting with the Marin County Sheriff’s Office to provide interim night shift coverage for up to six months. Belvedere’s Police Department is also actively recruiting for Reserve Police Officer positions. Reserve officers would be available to replace officers out...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New 5:30pm Starting Time: Council &amp; Planning Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-530pm-starting-time-council-planning-meetings/</link>
      <description>With their traditional starting time of 6:30pm, city meetings can run very late into the evening. To make it easier for residents to participate in person or by Zoom, the City Council adopted a 5:30pm start time for both City Council and Planning Commission meetings. The new starting time begins in September for Council and...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-530pm-starting-time-council-planning-meetings/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere: Make a Plan</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-make-a-plan/</link>
      <description>Emergency preparedness for the community is an important goal of the City Council. Last month you were asked to register for AlertMarin to receive emergency notifications. This month you are encouraged to Make a Plan with your family in case you are not together when disaster strikes.​ Agree on a place to meet if you...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-make-a-plan/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s the Belvedere Tiburon Library’s 30th Anniversary!</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/its-the-belvedere-tiburon-librarys-30th-anniversary/</link>
      <description>The Library is hosting TWO community events to celebrate their 30th anniversary, and you’re invited. Friday, September 5 from 5-7 pm Enjoy appetizers, wine, music, and photos celebrating the beginning at this adults only event. Sunday, September 7 from 12-3 pm This family-friendly party featuring kids’ entertainment, crafts, face painting, a jumpy house, food trucks,...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/its-the-belvedere-tiburon-librarys-30th-anniversary/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filmmaking Workshop: Saturday, August 30, 11am – 1pm</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/filmmaking-workshop-saturday-august-30-11am-1pm/</link>
      <description>Do you need a little help getting your short film in Oscar worthy shape before you submit for the second annual Belvedere Home Made Film Festival? Join the Film Fest team on Saturday, August 30 at 11am at the Belvedere Tiburon Library, where they will demonstrate various editing suites. Visit the Library website for more...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/filmmaking-workshop-saturday-august-30-11am-1pm/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last Concerts of the Season: Sunday, August 31</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/last-concerts-of-the-season-sunday-august-31/</link>
      <description>Labor Day Weekend will be the last opportunity this year to enjoy Concerts in the Park. On Sunday, August 31 come to Belvedere Park to dance and sing along to You Should Be Dancing – a timeless and captivating Bee Gee’s tribute band. The fun starts at 4pm. A big thanks to all the volunteers...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/last-concerts-of-the-season-sunday-august-31/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wildfire Prevention Festival: Saturday, September 6</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/wildfire-prevention-festival-saturday-september-6/</link>
      <description>On Saturday, September 6 from from 10am to 4pm at the Marin Civic Center Fairgrounds, the whole community is invited to learn how we can all prepare for wildfire. This free, family friendly event includes fire smart landscaping and home hardening exhibits, live burn demonstrations, and wildfire products and service providers. A kid zone, music,...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/wildfire-prevention-festival-saturday-september-6/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attention Drivers! Rules for School Bus Safety</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/attention-drivers-rules-for-school-bus-safety/</link>
      <description>As back-to-school season begins, school buses are back on the roads. This means drivers need to stay alert, informed and remember that the sole purpose of a school bus is to transport precious cargo- children. Below is a refresher of the California school bus rules to keep in mind: All traffic must stop when a...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/attention-drivers-rules-for-school-bus-safety/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere/</link>
      <description>Last fall, the City Council created the Be Ready Belvedere working group to address its vital goal of safety and emergency preparedness. Be Ready Belvedere, under the leadership of Councilmember Pat Carapiet, is currently working to finalize evacuation locations, obtain water and food to store at the designated spots, and update our local emergency medical...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New E-Bike Law in Effect in Belvedere &amp; Most of Marin</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-e-bike-law-in-effect-in-belvedere-most-of-marin/</link>
      <description>Did you know e-bike riders between 10 and 15 years old are five times more likely to be seriously injured than older riders? That’s why Marin County jurisdictions passed a new E-Bike Law that makes Class 2 throttle e-bikes off-limits to those under 16, and requires riders of all ages to wear helmets. This law...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-e-bike-law-in-effect-in-belvedere-most-of-marin/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registration is Open for Run Tiburon</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/registration-is-open-for-run-tiburon/</link>
      <description>Registration is now open for the September 7 Run Tiburon, a benefit for UCSF Courage over Cancer and The Ranch. With its views of Mt. Tam, the Golden Gate Bridge, Angel Island, and San Francisco Bay, this idyllic fall race is unlike any other. Register now!</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/registration-is-open-for-run-tiburon/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-3/</link>
      <description>At the June 9 City Council meeting, council members learned that the Mallard Pointe developers had signed a cost recovery agreement with the City of Belvedere -- allowing the planning staff to begin reviewing the various permit applications the developer has submitted. The first step in this review process involves identifying any incomplete or missing...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Department Staffing</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-staffing/</link>
      <description>Over the past two years, the Belvedere Police Department has faced several staffing setbacks, which have challenged its existing staffing and coverage model. Although Belvedere has six active officers in the budget -- Chief Jason Wu plus five duty officers -- due to a long-term disability leave, there are only four duty officers currently available....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-staffing/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New From Parks Open Spaces and Lanes Committee</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-from-parks-open-spaces-and-lanes-committee/</link>
      <description>Under the leadership of Chair Charlie Harrington, the Parks, Open Spaces and Lanes Committee (POSLC) is following its mission. At their June 12 meeting, the Committee was updated on the progress of creating a database that identifies all lanes and assesses their condition, value for evacuation and safety, and other benefits for the community. They...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-from-parks-open-spaces-and-lanes-committee/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>