<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>City of Belvedere News</title>
    <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news</link>
    <description>Official news and updates from the City of Belvedere, California</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 12:30:06 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</webMaster>
    <ns0:link href="https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>January 26th – 29th: Pile Burns Planned at Angel Island State Park</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/january-26th-29th-pile-burns-planned-at-angel-island-state-park/</link>
      <description>California State Parks is planning to conduct pile burn operations at Angel Island State Park, conditions permitting. These burns are being conducted to help manage invasive species, reduce fuel loading and to promote the resilience of the parks grasslands and oak woodlands in the event of future fires as part of State Park's Wildfire and...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/january-26th-29th-pile-burns-planned-at-angel-island-state-park/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Manager Report</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-manager-report/</link>
      <description>Thanks for pausing to read the Belvedere  Breeze! The City Council met this week to discuss the city’s budget, with a particular focus on how to thoughtfully allocate $1,030,000 in excess reserves for one-time operational and capital needs. Council approved $200,000 for several important projects—updates to Police Department facilities, debris removal along the Beach Road shoreline, and...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-manager-report/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 46th Annual Town Meeting: Tuesday, January 27</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/the-46th-annual-town-meeting-tuesday-january-27/</link>
      <description>Please join us at the Belvedere Community Center on Tuesday, January 27 from 6 to 7:30pm, to honor the 2025 Citizen of the Year Nancy Kemnitzer and the 2025 Citizen Emerita Pam Martori for thier outstanding contributions to the community. Also at this annual meeting, Mayor Sally Wilkinson and City Manager Robert Zadnik will share an...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/the-46th-annual-town-meeting-tuesday-january-27/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep Your Dog on the Right Side of the Law</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/keep-your-dog-on-the-right-side-of-the-law/</link>
      <description>Making sure your dog is licensed not only helps keep them safe - it's also required by law. Marin Humane is offering a new, easy-to-use licensing platform that provides effective pet identification and reunification services, helping keep pets out of shelters and return them home safely. Visit Marin Humane to purchase a new license or renew an existing one....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/keep-your-dog-on-the-right-side-of-the-law/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Your Garden Stay Varmint-Free: Tuesday, January 27</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/help-your-garden-stay-varmint-free-tuesday-january-27/</link>
      <description>Do you look out your window to find your roses beheaded? Are your carefully cultivated fruits and vegetables partially eaten? Or have some of your plants disappeared entirely? If so, your garden may be attracting deer, gophers, or rats. Join Lois Steven, a UC Marin Master Gardener since 2008, on January 27 at 11:00 a.m....</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/help-your-garden-stay-varmint-free-tuesday-january-27/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Retreat: Monday, February 23 at Noon</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-retreat-monday-february-23-at-noon/</link>
      <description>The City Council Retreat will be held on Monday, February 23, at the Belvedere Community Center, from noon to approximately 4pm. This planning session will focus on setting the city’s priorities, goals, and strategies for 2026. Community members are welcome to attend in person or via Zoom. Your interest and participation are always appreciated. If...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-retreat-monday-february-23-at-noon/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annual Firearm Safety Reminder from the Belvedere P.D.</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/annual-firearm-safety-reminder-from-the-belvedere-p-d/</link>
      <description>Securely storing firearms when not in use is an essential part of responsible gun ownership—and the most effective way to help prevent firearm accidents, theft, and misuse. Belvedere Municipal Code 9.7 requires all firearms to be properly secured when not in use, and California Penal Code 25100 makes an individual criminally liable if a loaded firearm is stored where...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/annual-firearm-safety-reminder-from-the-belvedere-p-d/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Leadership Update</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-leadership-update/</link>
      <description>At December’s meeting, the City Council continued Belvedere’s long-standing tradition of rotating leadership roles. Sally Wilkinson is our new Mayor, and Kevin Burke will serve as Vice Mayor in the year ahead. Both bring steady, thoughtful leadership and a deep appreciation for the community. We also extend a warm thank you to Jane Cooper for...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-leadership-update/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honoring Our 2025 Community Leaders</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/honoring-our-2025-community-leaders/</link>
      <description>Each year we honor two standout volunteers whose service helps Belvedere flourish. A group of past Citizens of the Year unanimously selected this year’s honorees. Our 2025 Citizen of the Year, Nancy Kemnitzer (pictured left), is recognized for more than 16 years of steady, thoughtful service on both the City Council and the Planning Commission. Her commitment...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/honoring-our-2025-community-leaders/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet Officer Tyler Preston</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/meet-officer-tyler-preston/</link>
      <description>Please join us in welcoming Officer Tyler Preston, the newest member of the Belvedere Police Department. Tyler grew up in Connecticut and began his public-safety career as a corrections officer while pursuing his college degree. His love of the outdoors eventually drew him west—visiting 26 national parks along the way—before he decided to make Northern...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/meet-officer-tyler-preston/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Give the Gift of Preparedness</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/give-the-gift-of-preparedness/</link>
      <description>If you’re still searching for a practical and meaningful holiday gift, consider assembling a Stay Box and Go Bag for your household. It’s a thoughtful way to support safety and peace of mind during an emergency. A well-stocked box includes several days’ worth of water, nonperishable food, a manual can opener, and basic cooking supplies. Add a...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/give-the-gift-of-preparedness/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Serve on the Mosquito &amp; Vector Control Board</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/serve-on-the-mosquito-vector-control-board/</link>
      <description>City Council is now accepting applications to fill one open seat on the Marin / Sonoma Mosquito and Vector Control District Board of Trustees. This board plays an important role in regional public health efforts. If you’re interested in being considered, please apply by January 5 with a brief letter of interest and qualifications. Applications...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/serve-on-the-mosquito-vector-control-board/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-5/</link>
      <description>At the November 10 City Council meeting, Councilmember Peter Mark, representative to the Transportation Authority of Marin (TAM), reported on a new program MASCOTS that will better coordinate public transportation from Sonoma through Marin by syncing bus, ferry, and SMART train schedules. For the Tiburon Peninsula, that means shorter wait times when connecting to buses...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-5/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belvedere Shifts Coyote Management to Marin Humane</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belvedere-shifts-coyote-management-to-marin-humane/</link>
      <description>For the past 3 years, Belvedere has listened to the concerns our residents have about coyotes and has responded in a variety of ways to address them. With the help of a wildlife consultant, the City Council adopted a Coyote Response Plan, learned what attracts coyotes to our community, and collected data on their number and...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belvedere-shifts-coyote-management-to-marin-humane/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere: Prepare for Winter Before it Arrives</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-prepare-for-winter-before-it-arrives/</link>
      <description>Storms can cause extensive damage to our homes and the surrounding community. Strategies for keeping your home safe during the winter include cleaning gutters and storm drains regularly, and trimming branches at risk of falling. For more, visit the city's Storm Preparation page. Flooding in Belvedere may occur when heavy rainfall is combined with a high tide. Storm...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-prepare-for-winter-before-it-arrives/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome New Public Works Hire Christian Rincon</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-public-works-hire-christian-rincon/</link>
      <description>After a rigorous public recruitment process, we are happy to announce that Belvedere's Public Works Department has hired Christian Rincon for the role of Public Works Maintenance Worker. Before joining the Belvedere team, Christian worked for the City of San Pablo as a maintenance worker. Christian says he's excited to be working in such a...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-public-works-hire-christian-rincon/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Aware of Fraudulent Email Requests for Payments</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-aware-of-fraudulent-email-requests-for-payments/</link>
      <description>Please be aware of a new email scam targeting customers of local Planning and Building Departments. If you receive a request for payment or information related to a building or planning project, DO NOT click any links or send money. Call the Belvedere Planning and Building Department at 415-435-3838 to ask if the email you received...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-aware-of-fraudulent-email-requests-for-payments/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere: Go Bags a Success</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-go-bags-a-success/</link>
      <description>As part of the City Council’s ongoing commitment to community preparedness, the Be Ready Belvedere team distributed 75 Go-Bag backpacks and emergency supplies to residents. An additional 20 backpacks were provided to staff for use in case they need to evacuate while at work. This successful event also shared important information about evacuation procedures and...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-go-bags-a-success/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New City Sweeper on the Streets</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-city-sweeper-on-the-streets/</link>
      <description>You may have noticed a new street sweeper in Belvedere in the past few weeks. The Public Works crew has been training on the recently purchased Ravo 5-iSeries, which is smaller, quieter, less dusty and has lower emissions. It can be seen in action on Thursdays and Fridays as the crew makes the rounds in...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-city-sweeper-on-the-streets/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reminder: Council &amp; Planning Meetings Begin at 5:30 PM</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/reminder-council-planning-meetings-begin-at-530-pm/</link>
      <description>Since September, City Council has been meeting at 5:30pm. And as of October 21, the Planning Commission also will start their meetings at this new, earlier time. Council meetings are held on the second Monday of each month and Planning Commission meetings on the third Tuesday of each month.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/reminder-council-planning-meetings-begin-at-530-pm/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>