<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>City of Belvedere News</title>
    <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news</link>
    <description>Official news and updates from the City of Belvedere, California</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 06:11:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</webMaster>
    <ns0:link href="https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Advisory: Eastbound &amp; Westbound Tiburon Blvd. Marin County Utility Potholing Project  Starts Monday, June 2,  8:00 PM-6:00 AM</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/traffic-advisory-eastbound-and-westbound-tiburon-blvd-sr-131-marin-county-utility-potholing-project-starts-monday-june-2-800-pm-600-am-monday-friday/</link>
      <description>Caltrans is scheduled to begin utility potholing on both directions of Tiburon Blvd. from U.S. 101 exit to Main street (approximately four miles). Workers will perform potholing on SR-131 to safely locate underground utilities (water, electrical, gas, telecommunications, and fiber optic lines) in preparation for the upcoming paving project of SR-131 scheduled in 2026. Eastbound...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/traffic-advisory-eastbound-and-westbound-tiburon-blvd-sr-131-marin-county-utility-potholing-project-starts-monday-june-2-800-pm-600-am-monday-friday/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connolly Calls for Rethink of Tiburon Blvd Bike Lanes</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/connolly-calls-for-rethink-of-tiburon-blvd-bike-lanes/</link>
      <description>Today, Belvedere City Manager and Mayor were cc’d on a letter to Caltrans from Assemblymember Damon Connolly, urging the agency to reconsider the inclusion of bike lanes in the Tiburon Blvd Capital Preventive Maintenance Project. Connolly—initially supportive of the bike lanes—listened to the voices of Tiburon Peninsula residents who participated in a letter-writing campaign to...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/connolly-calls-for-rethink-of-tiburon-blvd-bike-lanes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-2/</link>
      <description>The City Council reviewed the Preliminary 2025-26 Fiscal Year Budget. Key initiatives include significant sea wall repairs along Beach Road; integration of a new user fee schedule to enhance cost recovery; and launching a comprehensive infrastructure assessment. This budget continues the long-standing tradition of fiscal responsibility, maintaining city infrastructure, delivering high-quality services, and sustaining robust reserves to safeguard operations...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining a Fire-Smart Yard</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/maintaining-a-fire-smart-yard/</link>
      <description>Did you know most homes lost to wildfire are first ignited by embers from small fires nearby that then spread to the structure? Regular maintenance - including clearing away flammable debris and creating defensible space around your house - helps break the continuous fuel supply. This limits the potential for a small fire to escalate...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/maintaining-a-fire-smart-yard/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Curbside Vegetation Pick Up Begins May 20</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/free-curbside-vegetation-pick-up-begins-may-20/</link>
      <description>To help you rid your property of fire-prone vegetation and provide more defensible space around your home, Belvedere is offering its Annual Curbside Vegetation Pickup Program on six Tuesday mornings: May 20 through June 24. Place cut vegetation in a neat pile at the road edge in front of your property before 8am on one...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/free-curbside-vegetation-pick-up-begins-may-20/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome New Volunteers &amp; See More Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-volunteers-see-more-opportunities/</link>
      <description>At their May 12 meeting, the City Council interviewed three excellent candidates for one opening on the Planning Commission and is pleased to announce the appointment of Ghazaleh Jamei. The Council thanked Chair Ashley Johnson for serving four years on the Commission and wished her well in the next chapter of her life on the East Coast. And...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-volunteers-see-more-opportunities/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heads Up Parents of E-Bike Riders</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/heads-up-parents-of-e-bike-riders/</link>
      <description>A lengthy discussion at the May City Council meeting focused on a new e-bike ordinance for Belvedere. This ordinance will be adopted in June, and once it takes effect in July, minors under 16 can only ride Class 1 e-bikes. If you’re not sure if your child’s e-bike is Class 1, please: 1. Ensure the e-bike has a...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/heads-up-parents-of-e-bike-riders/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passes for Yellow Bus Program On Sale This Month</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/passes-for-yellow-bus-program-on-sale-this-month/</link>
      <description>There’s exciting news from the Tiburon Peninsula Traffic Alliance (TPTA) about the Yellow Bus Program for the 2025/26 school year. This program makes life easier for parents and helps reduce traffic congestion along Tiburon Boulevard for everyone. Afterschool Bus: A new late afternoon express bus for students participating in extracurricular activities at Bel Aire and Reed...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/passes-for-yellow-bus-program-on-sale-this-month/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerts in the Park Kicks off on Father’s Day: June 15</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/concerts-in-the-park-kicks-off-on-fathers-day-june-15/</link>
      <description>Bring the family to Belvedere Community Park on Sunday, June 15 at 4pm to dance and sing along with The Sun Kings, the Bay Area's favorite Beatles tribute band. This energetic group kicks off our 28th year of free summer concerts for the Belvedere community. Come join the fun! The concert series is sponsored by...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/concerts-in-the-park-kicks-off-on-fathers-day-june-15/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Opportunities!</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/volunteer-opportunities/</link>
      <description>The Belvedere City Council is now accepting letters of interest for vacancies on the following committees: The Historic Preservation Committee: 3 seats with four-year terms The Belvedere Tiburon Library Agency: 1 seat with a four-year term The Marin County Commission on Aging: 1 seat with a three-year term City Council will be interviewing candidates at...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/volunteer-opportunities/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates/</link>
      <description>Improving Belvedere’s Financial Stability: The City Council adopted revised user and regulatory fees for services provided by the Planning, Building, and Public Works departments. The fee increases reflected in the new schedule are based on a study conducted by ClearSource Financial Consulting, which analyzed fee revenues and related city costs over a 5-year period. The study found that...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New and Improved Yellow Bus Routes</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-and-improved-yellow-bus-routes-2/</link>
      <description>The Tiburon Peninsula Traffic Alliance (TPTA)—the team behind the Yellow Bus Challenge—is gearing up for the 2025–26 school year, and there’s lots of good news for Belvedere families. Del Mar Middle School routes have been updated with later morning departures and earlier afternoon returns – giving students more time in the morning and a quicker trip home....</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-and-improved-yellow-bus-routes-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Small Changes with Big Impacts for Earth Month</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/three-small-changes-with-big-impacts-for-earth-month/</link>
      <description>The City of Belvedere is moving forward with an item in our Climate Action Plan -- replacing one of our gas-powered Public Works trucks with a new electric vehicle – not only reducing our greenhouse gas emissions, but also saving the city thousands of dollars in gasoline. What are you going to do to make...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/three-small-changes-with-big-impacts-for-earth-month/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diana Maureen Receives Belvedere’s Spotlight Award</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/diana-maureen-receives-belvederes-spotlight-award/</link>
      <description>Everyone in Belvedere knows Diana’s gift shop on The Boardwalk. But did you know that Diana Maureen, a Tiburon resident since fourth grade, is the woman behind the name? After 10 years working at the local Standard Five and Dime in high school, college, and after graduation, she opened her eponymous store on March 1,...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/diana-maureen-receives-belvederes-spotlight-award/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>California’s Daylighting Law: No Parking Near Crosswalks</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/californias-daylighting-law-no-parking-near-crosswalks/</link>
      <description>California’s AB 417, known as the “Daylighting Law,” prohibits parking within 20 feet of any marked or unmarked crosswalk. The initiative aims to improve safety by keeping intersections clear of parked vehicles, enhancing visibility for both drivers and pedestrians. To help keep Belvedere walkers safe, on April 21, the Department of Public Works will begin...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/californias-daylighting-law-no-parking-near-crosswalks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Pedestrian Hybrid Beacon at Ned’s Way</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-pedestrian-hybrid-beacon-at-neds-way/</link>
      <description>On March 18, Caltrans activated a Pedestrian Hybrid Beacon on Tiburon Boulevard at Ned's Way, just like the one at Tiburon Boulevard and Stewart Drive. How it works: When a pedestrian presses the button, the signal flashes yellow, warning motorists to slow down. The signal will then become solid yellow, preparing motorists to stop. Next, the signal will turn solid...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-pedestrian-hybrid-beacon-at-neds-way/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Actions – March 10 Meeting</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-actions-march-10-meeting/</link>
      <description>Working to Improve Communication to Residents: Communications is a top priority for the City Council. Prior to developing a communication plan, which included revamping the city website and creating the Belvedere Breeze e-newsletter, we conducted a survey of residents in fall 2023. This year, to evaluate the impact of our various efforts to improvecommunication, we...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-actions-march-10-meeting/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sergeant Jeremy Clark Honored for Life Saving Effort</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/sergeant-jeremy-clark-honored-for-life-saving-effort/</link>
      <description>When Belvedere Police Sergeant Jeremy Clark heard the 9-1-1 report of an unconscious man on Beach Road, he sprang into action. Arriving on the scene before the EMTs, Sgt. Clark immediately administered CPR – saving the man’s life. In recognition of his rapid response to this emergency situation, Chief Jason Wu presented Sgt. Clark with...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/sergeant-jeremy-clark-honored-for-life-saving-effort/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Sewer Rehabilitation Project</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/upcoming-sewer-rehabilitation-project/</link>
      <description>This spring, Sanitary District 5 will be overseeing the 2025 Sewer Improvement Project, which consists of the rehabilitation of approximately 3,583 linear feet of deteriorated sewer in Belvedere and Tiburon. The work in Belvedere will be conducted in portions of Britton Ave, Golden Gate Ave, Beach Road, Madrona Ave, Bella Vista Ave and Toyon Ave....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/upcoming-sewer-rehabilitation-project/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Missed the Fire Safety Forum? View Online</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/missed-the-fire-safety-forum-view-online/</link>
      <description>​An overflow crowd of more than 115 residents from Belvedere and Tiburon attended last month’s Fire Preparation Forum. Every speaker - from Belvedere Police Chief Jason Wu to representatives from Tiburon Fire District and Marin County Office of Emergency Management -emphasized that the first critical step to prepare for any potential emergency is to register...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/missed-the-fire-safety-forum-view-online/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>