<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>City of Belvedere News</title>
    <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news</link>
    <description>Official news and updates from the City of Belvedere, California</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:15:23 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</webMaster>
    <ns0:link href="https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-5/</link>
      <description>At the November 10 City Council meeting, Councilmember Peter Mark, representative to the Transportation Authority of Marin (TAM), reported on a new program MASCOTS that will better coordinate public transportation from Sonoma through Marin by syncing bus, ferry, and SMART train schedules. For the Tiburon Peninsula, that means shorter wait times when connecting to buses...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-5/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Us Choose Our Citizens of the Year</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/help-us-choose-our-citizens-of-the-year/</link>
      <description>We need your help to choose Belvedere’s 2025 Citizen of the Year and Citizen Emeritus. Do you know someone who has generously volunteered their time and skills to make Belvedere the wonderful place it is - and maybe also has had an impact beyond our community? If so, we want to hear from you, so...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/help-us-choose-our-citizens-of-the-year/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belvedere Shifts Coyote Management to Marin Humane</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belvedere-shifts-coyote-management-to-marin-humane/</link>
      <description>For the past 3 years, Belvedere has listened to the concerns our residents have about coyotes and has responded in a variety of ways to address them. With the help of a wildlife consultant, the City Council adopted a Coyote Response Plan, learned what attracts coyotes to our community, and collected data on their number and...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belvedere-shifts-coyote-management-to-marin-humane/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere: Prepare for Winter Before it Arrives</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-prepare-for-winter-before-it-arrives/</link>
      <description>Storms can cause extensive damage to our homes and the surrounding community. Strategies for keeping your home safe during the winter include cleaning gutters and storm drains regularly, and trimming branches at risk of falling. For more, visit the city's Storm Preparation page. Flooding in Belvedere may occur when heavy rainfall is combined with a high tide. Storm...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-prepare-for-winter-before-it-arrives/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome New Public Works Hire Christian Rincon</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-public-works-hire-christian-rincon/</link>
      <description>After a rigorous public recruitment process, we are happy to announce that Belvedere's Public Works Department has hired Christian Rincon for the role of Public Works Maintenance Worker. Before joining the Belvedere team, Christian worked for the City of San Pablo as a maintenance worker. Christian says he's excited to be working in such a...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-public-works-hire-christian-rincon/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Aware of Fraudulent Email Requests for Payments</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-aware-of-fraudulent-email-requests-for-payments/</link>
      <description>Please be aware of a new email scam targeting customers of local Planning and Building Departments. If you receive a request for payment or information related to a building or planning project, DO NOT click any links or send money. Call the Belvedere Planning and Building Department at 415-435-3838 to ask if the email you received...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-aware-of-fraudulent-email-requests-for-payments/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Hall will be Closed for the Thanksgiving Holiday</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-hall-will-be-closed-for-the-thanksgiving-holiday/</link>
      <description>Belvedere City Hall will close at noon on Wednesday, November 26 and stay closed on Thursday, November 27 in observance of Thanksgiving. City Hall will reopen on Monday, December 1, at 8am.Inspections will only be available in the morningon Wednesday, November 26. Construction work is not allowed on Thursday, November 27 or Friday, November 28.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-hall-will-be-closed-for-the-thanksgiving-holiday/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Will Be Our Citizen of the Year &amp; Citizen Emeritus?</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/who-will-be-our-citizen-of-the-year-citizen-emeritus/</link>
      <description>Do you know a resident who has made a significant contribution to the community -- someone who has volunteered their time and skills to help make Belvedere the wonderful place that it is? We want to honor that person! The nomination process is now open for the Citizen of the Year and the Citizen Emeritus...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/who-will-be-our-citizen-of-the-year-citizen-emeritus/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere: Go Bags a Success</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-go-bags-a-success/</link>
      <description>As part of the City Council’s ongoing commitment to community preparedness, the Be Ready Belvedere team distributed 75 Go-Bag backpacks and emergency supplies to residents. An additional 20 backpacks were provided to staff for use in case they need to evacuate while at work. This successful event also shared important information about evacuation procedures and...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-go-bags-a-success/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New City Sweeper on the Streets</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-city-sweeper-on-the-streets/</link>
      <description>You may have noticed a new street sweeper in Belvedere in the past few weeks. The Public Works crew has been training on the recently purchased Ravo 5-iSeries, which is smaller, quieter, less dusty and has lower emissions. It can be seen in action on Thursdays and Fridays as the crew makes the rounds in...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-city-sweeper-on-the-streets/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reminder: Council &amp; Planning Meetings Begin at 5:30 PM</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/reminder-council-planning-meetings-begin-at-530-pm/</link>
      <description>Since September, City Council has been meeting at 5:30pm. And as of October 21, the Planning Commission also will start their meetings at this new, earlier time. Council meetings are held on the second Monday of each month and Planning Commission meetings on the third Tuesday of each month.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/reminder-council-planning-meetings-begin-at-530-pm/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BELNET: Daily Well-being Checks</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belnet-daily-well-being-checks/</link>
      <description>BELNET is a telephone welfare check program offered by the Belvedere Police Department for Belvedere's senior citizens. Residents who are registered will receive a daily call from the Police Department to find out how they are doing and if they need any assistance. This allows residents, and their families, to have peace of mind knowing...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/belnet-daily-well-being-checks/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lets Do Our Part to Keep Belvedere Clean</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/lets-do-our-part-to-keep-belvedere-clean/</link>
      <description>We live in one of the most beautiful cities in the world. Lets remember, Municipal Code (MC) 8.08.240 states that household trash containers must be maintained in a location that is not visible from the public street. On trash pick-up days, garbage cans, recycle containers and green compost bins may be placed on the street. However, they must be...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/lets-do-our-part-to-keep-belvedere-clean/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statewide Special Election: Tuesday, November 4</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/statewide-special-election-tuesday-november-4/</link>
      <description>By now, your November 4, 2025 Statewide Special Election ballot has either made it to your mailbox or is on its way. Once its ready, you can either put it in your mailbox or use the official drop box in front of the Belvedere Community Center (450 San Rafael Ave.) Need more information? You can check...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/statewide-special-election-tuesday-november-4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>News from the Parks, Open Spaces &amp; Lanes Committee</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news-from-the-parks-open-spaces-lanes-committee/</link>
      <description>The next time you stroll through Community Park or hike up one of our lanes, give a nod of thanks to Belvedere’s Parks, Open Spaces and Lanes Committee (POSLC). This volunteer committee collaborates closely with our Department of Public Works (DPW) to oversee and enhance city-owned property, including 23 lanes, 4 parks, the children’s playground...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news-from-the-parks-open-spaces-lanes-committee/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Department Upgrades to Flock Safety System</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-upgrades-to-flock-safety-system/</link>
      <description>This summer, Belvedere upgraded its automated license plate reader cameras to the Flock Safety System. Flock is widely adopted by Marin County law enforcement agencies and is becoming the industry standard throughout California. This new platform improves accuracy, has greater search capabilities, and integratesdirectly with surrounding agencies. This means our police can receive real-time alerts...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-upgrades-to-flock-safety-system/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-4/</link>
      <description>Police Department Update To address the recent staffing challenge, City Manager Zadnik reported that he is contracting with the Marin County Sheriff’s Office to provide interim night shift coverage for up to six months. Belvedere’s Police Department is also actively recruiting for Reserve Police Officer positions. Reserve officers would be available to replace officers out...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-4/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be Ready Belvedere: Make a Plan</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-make-a-plan/</link>
      <description>Emergency preparedness for the community is an important goal of the City Council. Last month you were asked to register for AlertMarin to receive emergency notifications. This month you are encouraged to Make a Plan with your family in case you are not together when disaster strikes.​ Agree on a place to meet if you...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/be-ready-belvedere-make-a-plan/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s the Belvedere Tiburon Library’s 30th Anniversary!</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/its-the-belvedere-tiburon-librarys-30th-anniversary/</link>
      <description>The Library is hosting TWO community events to celebrate their 30th anniversary, and you’re invited. Friday, September 5 from 5-7 pm Enjoy appetizers, wine, music, and photos celebrating the beginning at this adults only event. Sunday, September 7 from 12-3 pm This family-friendly party featuring kids’ entertainment, crafts, face painting, a jumpy house, food trucks,...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/its-the-belvedere-tiburon-librarys-30th-anniversary/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attention Drivers! Rules for School Bus Safety</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/attention-drivers-rules-for-school-bus-safety/</link>
      <description>As back-to-school season begins, school buses are back on the roads. This means drivers need to stay alert, informed and remember that the sole purpose of a school bus is to transport precious cargo- children. Below is a refresher of the California school bus rules to keep in mind: All traffic must stop when a...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/attention-drivers-rules-for-school-bus-safety/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>