<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>City of Belvedere News</title>
    <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/news</link>
    <description>Official news and updates from the City of Belvedere, California</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 12:15:24 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <managingEditor>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>clerk@cityofbelvedere.org (City of Belvedere)</webMaster>
    <ns0:link href="https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-3/</link>
      <description>At the June 9 City Council meeting, council members learned that the Mallard Pointe developers had signed a cost recovery agreement with the City of Belvedere -- allowing the planning staff to begin reviewing the various permit applications the developer has submitted. The first step in this review process involves identifying any incomplete or missing...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-3/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Department Staffing</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-staffing/</link>
      <description>Over the past two years, the Belvedere Police Department has faced several staffing setbacks, which have challenged its existing staffing and coverage model. Although Belvedere has six active officers in the budget -- Chief Jason Wu plus five duty officers -- due to a long-term disability leave, there are only four duty officers currently available....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/police-department-staffing/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New From Parks Open Spaces and Lanes Committee</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-from-parks-open-spaces-and-lanes-committee/</link>
      <description>Under the leadership of Chair Charlie Harrington, the Parks, Open Spaces and Lanes Committee (POSLC) is following its mission. At their June 12 meeting, the Committee was updated on the progress of creating a database that identifies all lanes and assesses their condition, value for evacuation and safety, and other benefits for the community. They...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/new-from-parks-open-spaces-and-lanes-committee/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Housing Element Update</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/housing-element-update/</link>
      <description>The City’s Housing Element has been updated in response to the California Department of Housing &amp; Community Development's (HCD) January 14 comment letter. A redlined version of the document, with edits in yellow, is on the city’s website. HCD has indicated their informal approval of the proposed revisions, signaling that the changes address all remaining...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/housing-element-update/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E-Bike Law Adopted: Riders Must be 16+ and Wear Helmet</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/e-bike-law-adopted-riders-must-be-16-and-wear-helmet/</link>
      <description>On Monday, City Council adopted an ordinance restricting the age of Class 2 e-bike riders to 16 and older and requiring all Class 2 or Class 3 e-bike riders to wear a helmet. Class 2 e-bikes are operated with a throttle and do not have pedal assist. Class 1 e-bikes, which are pedal-assisted and do...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/e-bike-law-adopted-riders-must-be-16-and-wear-helmet/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome New Volunteers!</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-volunteers/</link>
      <description>At their June 9 meeting, City Council reappointed Roxanne Richards to the Belvedere Tiburon Library Agency Board for another term, and reappointed Larry Binkley to the Marin County Commission on Aging for another term. Council also appointed two alternate members to the Planning Commission: retired Commissioner Marsha Lasky and Belvedere resident Isolde Wilson. Please join...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-volunteers/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coyote Hazing Strategies: Simple Yet Effective</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/coyote-hazing-strategies-simple-yet-effective-2/</link>
      <description>Simple, home-made deterrents can help keep coyotes fearful of humans, while also protecting you and your dog when out for a walk. An easy-to-carry &quot;scare stick&quot;, a plastic trash bag, an empty soda can with pennies, and even a loud yell can be very effective tools for hazing coyotes. For an explanation of these tools...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/coyote-hazing-strategies-simple-yet-effective-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eco Events at the Library: Friday June 20 &amp; Saturday 21</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/eco-events-at-the-library-friday-june-20-saturday-21/</link>
      <description>Safely Dispose of your Old Electronics Clear out your clutter and help protect the environment on Friday, June 20, from 1 to 4pm. Just drive into the Bel-Tib Library parking lot, drop off your old electronics, and they will be recycled responsibly. For a list of what’s accepted, and what isn’t, visit the event’s webpage....</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/eco-events-at-the-library-friday-june-20-saturday-21/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Juneteenth Celebration in Tiburon: Sunday June 22</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/juneteenth-celebration-in-tiburon-sunday-june-22/</link>
      <description>Make your way to Main St. on Sunday, June 22 from 3 to 7pm for our local celebration of Juneteenth – a holiday of remembrance and empowerment. This free community event features live jazz and hip hop, poetry readings, guest speakers, great food and so much more. This Diversity Inclusion Task Force event is made...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/juneteenth-celebration-in-tiburon-sunday-june-22/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of 101 Northbound Onramps Metering Lights</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/activation-of-101-northbound-onramps-metering-lights/</link>
      <description>To reduce congestion, improve traffic flow, and enhance safety on Highway 101, Caltrans will activate ramp metering lights in Marin County starting this month. Although the signal lights for the northbound 101 onramps at Tiburon Blvd. have been in place since 2020, they will officially become operational on Tuesday, June 24. The ramp metering will...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/activation-of-101-northbound-onramps-metering-lights/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Advisory: Eastbound &amp; Westbound Tiburon Blvd. Marin County Utility Potholing Project  Starts Monday, June 2,  8:00 PM-6:00 AM</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/traffic-advisory-eastbound-and-westbound-tiburon-blvd-sr-131-marin-county-utility-potholing-project-starts-monday-june-2-800-pm-600-am-monday-friday/</link>
      <description>Caltrans is scheduled to begin utility potholing on both directions of Tiburon Blvd. from U.S. 101 exit to Main street (approximately four miles). Workers will perform potholing on SR-131 to safely locate underground utilities (water, electrical, gas, telecommunications, and fiber optic lines) in preparation for the upcoming paving project of SR-131 scheduled in 2026. Eastbound...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/traffic-advisory-eastbound-and-westbound-tiburon-blvd-sr-131-marin-county-utility-potholing-project-starts-monday-june-2-800-pm-600-am-monday-friday/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connolly Calls for Rethink of Tiburon Blvd Bike Lanes</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/connolly-calls-for-rethink-of-tiburon-blvd-bike-lanes/</link>
      <description>Today, Belvedere City Manager and Mayor were cc’d on a letter to Caltrans from Assemblymember Damon Connolly, urging the agency to reconsider the inclusion of bike lanes in the Tiburon Blvd Capital Preventive Maintenance Project. Connolly—initially supportive of the bike lanes—listened to the voices of Tiburon Peninsula residents who participated in a letter-writing campaign to...</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/connolly-calls-for-rethink-of-tiburon-blvd-bike-lanes/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Council Goals &amp; Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-2/</link>
      <description>The City Council reviewed the Preliminary 2025-26 Fiscal Year Budget. Key initiatives include significant sea wall repairs along Beach Road; integration of a new user fee schedule to enhance cost recovery; and launching a comprehensive infrastructure assessment. This budget continues the long-standing tradition of fiscal responsibility, maintaining city infrastructure, delivering high-quality services, and sustaining robust reserves to safeguard operations...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/city-council-goals-updates-2/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining a Fire-Smart Yard</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/maintaining-a-fire-smart-yard/</link>
      <description>Did you know most homes lost to wildfire are first ignited by embers from small fires nearby that then spread to the structure? Regular maintenance - including clearing away flammable debris and creating defensible space around your house - helps break the continuous fuel supply. This limits the potential for a small fire to escalate...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/maintaining-a-fire-smart-yard/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free Curbside Vegetation Pick Up Begins May 20</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/free-curbside-vegetation-pick-up-begins-may-20/</link>
      <description>To help you rid your property of fire-prone vegetation and provide more defensible space around your home, Belvedere is offering its Annual Curbside Vegetation Pickup Program on six Tuesday mornings: May 20 through June 24. Place cut vegetation in a neat pile at the road edge in front of your property before 8am on one...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/free-curbside-vegetation-pick-up-begins-may-20/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome New Volunteers &amp; See More Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-volunteers-see-more-opportunities/</link>
      <description>At their May 12 meeting, the City Council interviewed three excellent candidates for one opening on the Planning Commission and is pleased to announce the appointment of Ghazaleh Jamei. The Council thanked Chair Ashley Johnson for serving four years on the Commission and wished her well in the next chapter of her life on the East Coast. And...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/welcome-new-volunteers-see-more-opportunities/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heads Up Parents of E-Bike Riders</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/heads-up-parents-of-e-bike-riders/</link>
      <description>A lengthy discussion at the May City Council meeting focused on a new e-bike ordinance for Belvedere. This ordinance will be adopted in June, and once it takes effect in July, minors under 16 can only ride Class 1 e-bikes. If you’re not sure if your child’s e-bike is Class 1, please: 1. Ensure the e-bike has a...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/heads-up-parents-of-e-bike-riders/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passes for Yellow Bus Program On Sale This Month</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/passes-for-yellow-bus-program-on-sale-this-month/</link>
      <description>There’s exciting news from the Tiburon Peninsula Traffic Alliance (TPTA) about the Yellow Bus Program for the 2025/26 school year. This program makes life easier for parents and helps reduce traffic congestion along Tiburon Boulevard for everyone. Afterschool Bus: A new late afternoon express bus for students participating in extracurricular activities at Bel Aire and Reed...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/passes-for-yellow-bus-program-on-sale-this-month/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concerts in the Park Kicks off on Father’s Day: June 15</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/concerts-in-the-park-kicks-off-on-fathers-day-june-15/</link>
      <description>Bring the family to Belvedere Community Park on Sunday, June 15 at 4pm to dance and sing along with The Sun Kings, the Bay Area's favorite Beatles tribute band. This energetic group kicks off our 28th year of free summer concerts for the Belvedere community. Come join the fun! The concert series is sponsored by...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/concerts-in-the-park-kicks-off-on-fathers-day-june-15/</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer Opportunities!</title>
      <link>https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/volunteer-opportunities/</link>
      <description>The Belvedere City Council is now accepting letters of interest for vacancies on the following committees: The Historic Preservation Committee: 3 seats with four-year terms The Belvedere Tiburon Library Agency: 1 seat with a four-year term The Marin County Commission on Aging: 1 seat with a three-year term City Council will be interviewing candidates at...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.cityofbelvedere.org/volunteer-opportunities/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>